Mario Altagracia Jimenez

Austin, TX | 512-994-1887 | Jimernez.io@gmail.com | Github.com/Toughee | Toughee.com

Summary

Freelance Developer primarily focused on front end development. Experienced in building web applications emphasizing on responsive design and seamless user interfaces. Able to adjust myself in any team environment, possessing excellent communication skills, and capable of learning any tool or software needed complete any work assigned to me or my team. Supporter and contributor to free and open source software projects.

Work Experience

Help Desk Agent / Reception

November 2017 - Present

Holiday Inn Express

Austin, TX

Durham, NC

On site tech support for hotel guests and clients staying inside the hotel

- Resolved daily troubleshooting and networking issues
- Helped with 80% of connectivity and I.P related issues in a 7 month period
- Fixed browser issues for company desktop computers

Web Developer

November 2016 – June 2017

Code for America

Collaborative nonprofit position for the City of Durham, North Carolina

- Resolved U/I issues and refined U/X for the web application
- Launch complete application for public use before deadline
- Fixed website issues on a weekly basis

Assistant Data scientist

September 2015 - July 2016

San Juan, P.R

Sacred Heart University Library

Assistant position inside University's Library system

- Cataloged library items inside University's database
- Completed a weekly server inspection for all library items

Founder and Web Developer

November 2013 - May 2014

San Juan, P.R

Sx3 Consulting Firm

Independent Startup company focused on media and entertainment industry

- Worked on contract creating website designs, mockups and branding illustrations
- Collaborated with a national media platform to produce weekly client work
- Created successful branding strategies for different clients

Technical Skills

Web languages: HTML5, CSS3, Python, JavaScript

Frameworks / Libraries: Bootstrap, Django, React, Ruby on Rails

Version Control: Git **CMS:** Wordpress

Servers and Databases: MySQL, npm, PHP **Operating Systems:** macOS, Linux, Windows

Collaboration tools: Slack, Github

Education

Sacred Heart University, B.A in **Advertising**

Aug 2011 – May 2016 San Juan, P.R